A Guide to the Aldie Horticultural Society Records, 1923-2013
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
Aldie Horticultural Society Records, 1923-2013
Thomas Balch Library
M 009
1 cu. ft
Photocopies of minutes, roll call records, programs, and brochures of places visited by the members of the Aldie Horticultural Society from 1923-2013.
Aldie Horticultural Society
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Provenance
Aldie Horticultural Society, Aldie, VA
Alternative Form Available
None
Accruals
1997.0001; 2013.0149
Historical Information
On 9 Mar 1923 seventeen women met at the home of Mrs. John Moore (n.d.) and decided to establish the Aldie Horticultural Society. Mrs. Floyd (Eleanor Truax) Harris (1868-1937), was elected president, and the group agreed to meet monthly. Records show that the group has met on a regular basis to hear presentations on topics of interest to gardeners, to undertake projects to beautify various sites in Aldie, to visit gardens of interest, and to sponsor shows of several varieties of plants, including a yearly daffodil show for members of the society. Mrs. Harris developed the Stoke Daffodil, named for her home, Stoke.
The organization, which is not associated with Garden Clubs of Virginia, meets on a regular basis. Ongoing civic activities include sending two Aldie children to nature camp each year, and decorating the town of Aldie, VA for Christmas. A long term project has been to send money for treats to a senior citizens' home in Manassas, VA for the Fourth of July.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of photocopies of minutes, roll call records, programs, and brochures of places visited by the members of the society from 1923-2013. The originals of these records were retained by the society.
Folders 1-11 contain the minutes of meetings of years 1923-1933. Folders 12 -16 contain the minutes for 1937-1941. Minutes in Folder 18 go back to 1933; folders 19-22 contain records for 1934-1937.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Aldie Horticultural Society Records (M 009), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Interview, Mrs. Frederick Warren, 2006.
Other Finding Aid
None
Related Material
None
Contents List
- (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1923
  - Minutes, 1924
  - Minutes, 1925
  - Minutes, 1926
  - Minutes, 1927
  - Minutes, 1928
  - Minutes, 1929
  - Minutes, 1930
  - Minutes, 1931
  - Minutes, 1932
  - Minutes, Apr 1933
  - Minutes, 1937
  - Minutes, 1938
  - Minutes, 1939
  - Minutes, 1940
  - Minutes, 1941
  - Roll Call; articles regarding the death of Mrs. Floyd Harris 1923-1941
  - Minutes, Oct, Nov 1933
  - Minutes, 1934
  - Minutes, 1935
  - Minutes, 1936
  - Minutes, 1937
  - Minutes, 1942
  - Minutes, 1943
  - Minutes, 1944
  - Minutes, 1945-1946
  - Minutes, 1947
  - Minutes, 1948
  - Minutes, 1949
  - Minutes,1950
  - Minutes, 1951
  - Minutes, 1952
  - Minutes, 1953
  - Minutes, 1954
  - Minutes, 1955
- (Box 2)
  - Minutes, 1956
  - Minutes, 1957
  - Minutes, 1958
  - Minutes, 1959
  - Minutes, 1960
  - Roll Call, 1942-1960
  - Minutes, 1961-1963, Roll Call 1961-1964
  - Minutes, 1964-1965
  - Minutes, 1966
  - Minutes, 1967
  - Minutes, 1968
  - Minutes, Program, 1969
  - Minutes, Program, 1970
  - Minutes, Program, 1971
  - Minutes, Program, 1972
  - Minutes, Program, 1973
  - Minutes, Program, 1974
  - Minutes, Program, 1975
  - Minutes, Program, 1976
  - Minutes, 1977
- (Box 3)
  - Minutes, 1978
  - Minutes, 1979
  - Minutes, 1980
  - Minutes, 1981
  - Minutes, 1968-1971
  - Minutes, 1982
  - Minutes, 1983
  - Minutes, 1984
  - Minutes, Program, 1985
  - Minutes, Program, 1986
  - Minutes, Program, 1987
  - Minutes, Program, 1988
  - Minutes, Program
  - Minutes, Program
  - Minutes, Program, Roll Call, 1982-1991
  - "A History of Aldie Horticultural Society: The First 90 Years," 15 September 2013